我们都知道结局会如何  对吗
We all know how this ends, don't we?
全军覆没
Everybody dies.
这应该算不上是意外
That shouldn't be a surprise.
所以一个有着一生博学
So what's an old, white man to do
却注定要抹去的白人老头
with a lifetime of knowledge,
能做什么呢
doomed to erasure,
除了把它当做剑来使用
except wield it like a sword?
伟人说放手一搏
Great men say balls to death.
我的团队尊重这点
My crew respect that.
早上好  亲爱的家人
Good morning, dear family.
起床了
Rise and shine.
我们距离出发已经过去了2468天
We are 2,468 days from departure,
3天前和雪国列车重接在了一起
and three days since reconnection.
献给一个特别的战友
For a special comrade,
我选择了圣-桑的
I have chosen Camille Saint-Saens'
《狮子皇家进行曲》
"Royal March of the Lions."
我们是狮子
We are lions,
前来从一群鬣狗手中
here to reclaim our Engine Eternal
夺回我们的永动机
from a gibbering pack of hyenas.
我们的自尊心悄悄靠近  等待
Our pride stalks, waits,
你们每个人都在
each of you playing your part
伟大远行中扮演着自己的角色
in a great odyssey.
有的人会比别人付出更高的代价
Some pay a higher cost than others,
我们中没有谁比冷淡鲍勃
and none among us have paid more
付出的代价更大
than Icy Bob.
我们都应该像鲍勃一样做出牺牲
We should all make sacrifices like our Bob,
磨炼我们的意图
honing our purpose to the ready.
让我们的冷冻人团结我们
Let our Coldman unite us,
我们的矛尖
the point of our spear...
在我们重新夺回
For the day we retake
属于我的东西的那天
what's mine.
末日其实并没那么糟
Apocalypse isn't so bad, really.
如果你能勉强蒙混过关
If you can just muddle through,
展示出一点独创性
show a little ingenuity,
人们就会为了城里唯一的演出
people line up for tickets
而排成长龙
to the only show in town--
雪国列车车上
aboard Snowpiercer.
我的列车
My train.
1034节车厢
All 1,034 cars long.
雪国列车
第二季 第三集
"浩瀚长征"
面对怀疑  快速站立
Standing fast, in the face of doubt,
尤其是自己的怀疑
especially your own.
-领袖必须这么做  -我知道  可是...
- It's what a leader has to do. - Sure, but...
不该是一个母亲该做的事
it's not what a mother should do.
如果大地母亲要复活
If Mother Earth is coming back to life,
那么是的  母亲应该这么做
then yes, it's what a mother should do.
一个月
One month.
再过大约一小时  我们就要换轨道  驶向西边
About an hour left until we switch track and head west.
早餐好了
Breakfast is served.
让雪国列车开过那座山
It's going to be a shit show
会异常艰难
getting Snowpiercer over that mountain.
他们能闻到我们的鸡蛋
They smell our eggs, you know.
现在他们比从前更渴望新鲜事物
Now they're craving fresh food like never before.
很好
Good.
人人都得保持饥饿
Everyone needs to stay hungry.
伤疤可以提醒你你愿意付出多少
Hmm, a scar to remind you how far you're willing to go.
它只提醒了我
All it does is remind me
梅兰妮试图背叛我们
that Melanie flipped the tables on us.
我知道
I know!
可靠科学  地球可能会回暖
Sound science that the Earth may be warming.
太棒了
It's fabulous.
而她即将踏上一次真正的自杀任务
And she's departing on a veritable suicide mission,
把我们可怕的革命者莱顿先生抛在后面
leaving Mr. Layton, our fearsome revolutionary!
我好激动
I'm tingling.
这会比割开他的喉咙
This will be far more fun
有意思得多
than simply slitting his throat.
大爱丽丝  收到吗  这里是雪国列车
Big Alice, do you copy? This is Snowpiercer.
终于听到你们的声音真好
Well, it's lovely to finally hear your voices.
这是落基山脉旧测试轨道
This is the old Rocky Mountain Test Track.
别名碎颈轨道
AKA Neckbreaker.
但我向你保证  比听上去危险得多
But I assure you, it's much more dangerous than it sounds.
这个高点是我们能开到距离研究站最近的地方
This high point here is as close as we can get to the station.
不  雪国列车才是问题所在
No, Snowpiercer is the problem.
我们刚开过碎颈轨道  那条轨道没问题
We just came over Neckbreaker. That track is sound.
但因为雪国列车必须为伯绍德曲线降速
But because Snowpiercer has to slow for the Berthoud Curve,
我们将没有足够的速度爬上山
we won't have enough speed to get up the mountain.
但一旦我们通过曲线
But once we're through the curve,
大爱丽丝就可以激活我们的助推器
Big Alice can activate our booster,
可以给我们足够的转力  让我们开过去
can give us just enough torque to take us over.
-没错  -如果不成呢
- That's correct. - And if it doesn't work?
如果不成呢
"If it doesn't work?"
是你吗  莱顿先生
Is that you, Mr. Layton?
你怎么跟工程师们在一起
Whatever are you doing among the Engineers?
平民监督  威尔福德先生
Civilian oversight, Mr. Wilford.
这是现在我们这的规矩
That's how it goes up here now.
如果不成功会发生这些情况
What happens if it doesn't work is this:
我们必须倒车离开那里
we have to reverse out of there,
环绕世界一圈  再从另一个方向过去
go around the world, and come at it from the other direction.
我们可不希望那样
Oh, we don't want that.
梅兰妮会错失逃生的时机
Melanie will miss her window to jump ship
为拯救世界而牺牲
and die saving the world.
对吗  梅兰妮
Won't you, Melanie?
对  我们会错过这机会
Yes, we would miss this opportunity.
事实就是我们没有那么多时间
And the truth is we don't have the luxury of time.
好了  那就是计划  我们开始吧
Okay, so that's the plan. Let's get to work.
露丝会送一份物资清单给你
Ruth is sending you a list of supplies.
这不是正确的静止列车
This isn't the right stationary.
请允许我和本上车拉设备
I would like permission to come aboard with Ben to pull equipment.
本不能上车
Nope. Not Ben.
真的吗  为什么本不能
Oh, really? And why not Ben?
因为大爱丽丝是禁本区  本
Because Big Alice is a Ben-Free Zone, Ben.
那艾莉克斯可以帮我
Then Alex can help me.
好吧  把清单送过来
Very well. Send me your list.
我在边境等你  亲自搜你身
I'll meet you at the border and frisk you myself.
好的
Good.
我们抵达落基山脉之前
Well, we have a thousand kilometers
有一千公里废弃直线轨道
of dead straight track before the Rockies.
我们看看两个火车头能做成什么
Let's see what two engines can do.
冲啊  冲啊
Vamos, vamos.
我们离开主轨道了  正开往落基山脉
We've left the main track. Heading for the Rockies.
威尔福德会借这些物资压榨我们的
Hey, Wilford's gonna squeeze us for these supplies.
我们仍需要零件维护雪国列车
And we still need parts for Snowpiercer.
我有个主意
Yeah, I got an idea for that.
我和你一起去边境
I'm gonna come with you up to the border.
我要去送物资清单
I have a list of supplies to deliver.
-谢谢  露丝  -谢我什么
- Thank you, Ruth. - What for?
害我们要去落基山脉执行自杀任务吗
Helping drag us into the Rockies on a suicide mission?
我还是留给你吧
I'll leave that to you.
她没让你好过  对吧
She doesn't make it easy on you, does she?
我的建议是别骗她
My advice? Don't lie to her.
我后悔骗过她  而且我可能没机会补救了
I regret that I did, and I'll probably never make it right,
但对你来说
but for you,
如果你能留住她  她是少见的正直之人
she's a rare straight arrow if you can keep her.
请让开  罗切先生
Make way, Mr. Roche.
你最好去边境
And best make your way to the border.
为什么  发生什么事了
Why? What's going on?
工程师和山脉  几乎和他们的自负一样大
Engineers and mountains, almost as big as their egos.
下雪时我们会到达哪里
Where will we land when the snow settles?
但愿是和我妻子在卧铺上  手里拿着冰啤酒
Hopefully on a couchette, with my wife and a cold beer.
老大
Hey, Boss.
我已经不是你的老大了
I'm not your boss anymore.
你在这里睡觉吗
You sleep in here?
单身生活  记得吗
Single life, remember?
我和我的二等厢房间分手了
I broke up with my Second Class cabin.
你是列车警探
You're Train Detective.
莱顿应该能帮你找个卧铺吧
Layton should be able to find you a berth, for Pete's sake.
但我有更重要的问题要解决
Yeah, well, I got more important issues.
什么  那起车尾人袭击吗
What? That Tailie assault?
情况不妙
It ain't good.
边境有大麻烦
Well, there's much ado about something at the border,
我们去找他
so let's go find him.
橡胶印章  你看她
Rubber stamps. I mean, look at her.
现在车尾人要怎么运大麻
How's a Tailie supposed to move a little weed now?
会成功的
It'll work.
可能会成功
It might work.
我就想引他的人上钩
I just want to set the hook in his people.
女士们先生们  这是进步的铃声
Ladies and gentlemen, the bell of progress.
边境有电话了
A hotline at the border,
两辆火车能通讯
and communication between the engines.
大家现在都规矩点
Let's all be on our best now.
早上好  大爱丽丝
Good morning, Big Alice.
我是雪国列车乘客服务部的主管
This is Snowpiercer's Head of Hospitality.
我们准备好过境了
We are clear for crossing.
早上好
Good morning.
这事不是应该凯文来做吗
Shouldn't Kevin be doing this?
-我来  -可怜的凯文病了
- I'm doing it. - Poor Kevin is ill.
一定是在你那边染上了
Must have picked up something unsanitary
不卫生的东西  莱顿先生
over there with you, Mr. Layton.
你看过你友敌的购物清单了吗
Have you seen your frenemy's shopping list?
看了  先生
Yes, sir. I have.
你想要六个氧化还原流电池  梅兰妮
You want six redox flow batteries, Melanie?
没错
That's right.
-艾莉克斯呢  -她在帮你准备降落伞
- Where's Alex? - Oh, she's packing your chute.
你紧张吗
Are you nervous?
-我可以给你四块  -不行  六块我都要
- You can have four. - No, I need all six.
这样我才能熬过最开始的24小时
So I can make it through the first 24 hours
并重新启动研究站
and get the station powered up.
我不能给你一个高压雪橇
Well, I'm not giving you a volt sled.
我很确定你有三个高压雪橇
Pretty sure you have three volt sleds.
没错  我有三个
Yes, I have three volt sleds,
但如果我给你一个
but if I give you one,
我就只剩两个了  对吧
I'll only have two, won't I?
其实先生  那只是梅兰妮的清单
Actually, sir, that's just Melanie's list.
据我所知雪国列车需要零件
Snowpiercer is in need of parts, as I understand,
尤其是那个
particularly the, um--the--
-转向架引擎  -转向架引擎
- Bogie motors. - Bogie motors.
我听说是三个
Three, I'm told.
那些很重要  鉴于我们现在都在同一列车上了
They're pretty important, seeing as we're all one train now,
所以我想我们或许能做个交易
so I thought that maybe we could work out a trade.
一些新鲜水果  蔬菜
Some fresh fruit, vegetables.
面包  鸡蛋  一瓶苹果酒
Bread, eggs, a jug of apple cider.
我们每周给你们供应一次食物
We will supplement your diet once a week
以此交换零件
in exchange for parts.
你似乎是个能干的领导
You seem like a capable leader.
我很意外你在这么短时间内
Amazing what you've learned
长进了这么多
in such a short time.
我会考虑的
I'll consider it.
我需要在14小时后用高压雪橇  约瑟夫
And I'm leaving on a volt sled in 14 hours, Joseph.
请求上车
Permission to board.
乘客服务部很乐意护送  先生
Hospitality will be happy to escort, Sir.
很遗憾  今天不行  露丝  会轮到你的
Regretfully, not today, Ruth. You'll get your turn.
带她过来
Bring her in.
再会  莱顿先生
Adieu, Mr. Layton.
很快  就只有你和他了
Pretty soon, it's just you and him.
27节补给列车  梅兰妮
27 cars of supplies, Melanie.
27节
27.
所有的零件
All the bits and bobs.
生命的原料
The stuff of life.
生存的希望大大提升了
Well, the chances of survival just got a lot better.
变暖趋势
A warming trend.
真是天才
Genius.
我整晚没睡  想着你的假设
I was up all night mulling your hypothesis.
这很合理  海德伍德夫妇同意
It's plausible. The Headwoods agree.
那就下定决心去做  因为如果我们能改变气候
Then put your mind to it 'cause if we can model it,
那或许我们就能建立第一个殖民地
then maybe we can build our first colony.
放心  我同意
Please, I'm aboard.
厉害  你让整列车充满了希望
Bravo, you filled the train with hope.
只可惜你要为数据而冻死了
It's just sad you're gonna freeze to death for data.
-你也觉得这既悲伤又滑稽吗  艾莉克斯  -不
- You find that tragic-comic, too, Alex? - No.
不会  只有要六块液流电池  她就会没事
No, with six RFBs, she'll be fine.
那太可惜了
Oh, what a shame.
前提是你能到达研究站
If you can make it to the station.
对
Yeah.
对  那是第一个难关
Yeah, that's the, um, first hurdle.
你走吧  达布斯
You can go, Dubs.
我来就行
I've got her.
你会陷入深厚  漂移的雪中
You'll be in deep, drifted snow.
如果你要绕过任何裂缝或雪崩残骸
If you have to detour through any crevasses or avalanche debris,
你的雪橇就可能在
your sled could be out of fuel
到达研究站时耗尽能量
by the time you get to the station.
雪橇可以没有能量
Well, the sled can stay dead
直到我必须回到轨道再说
until I have to get back to the track.
不  因为我们不知道他们的太阳能板退化了多少
No, because we don't know how degraded their solar panels are,
你的数据系统需要一个可靠的能量源
and your data systems need a reliable power source
才能建立气候类型
to create a climate model.
我会搞定的
I'll get it done.
把电压表给我
Pass me that volt meter.
我还没在爱丽丝上看见其他孩子
I haven't seen any other kids on Alice.
那是因为我是最年轻的
Well, that would be 'cause I'm the youngest crew member.
你有朋友吗
Do you have any friends?
你觉得接下去几小时
Just what do you think is going to happen here
会发生什么
over the next few hours?
-越多越好  -挺讽刺的  对吧
- As much as possible. - Kind of ironic, right?
因为我们在这帮你收拾东西
'Cause we're here packing your shit
只为了让你再次离开我
so that you can leave me again.
这比讽刺更糟
It's worse than ironic.
令人心碎
It's awful.
我很抱歉
And I'm sorry.
你离开一次  那是决定
You leave once, that's a decision.
然后你离开我两次  那就变成了选择
Then, you leave me twice, and then that becomes a choice.
对  我选择离开
Yes, I'm choosing to go,
但只是因为如果我不走
but only because there's not much chance
你的未来就没有盼头
of a world for you if I don't.
好吧  那么
Okay, so...
你想知道什么
what do you wanna know?
一切
Everything.
你喜欢干什么
What do you love to do?
谁帮你打的耳洞
Who pierced your ears?
你在哪睡觉
Where you sleep.
你会笑吗
Will you ever laugh?
好吧
Okay.
我带你去看看我睡觉的地方
I'll show you where I sleep.
来
Come on.
她不想迈尔斯看到她
She doesn't want Miles to see her.
她什么都知道  孩子
She knows everything, mi hijo.
真对不起  乔茜
I'm so sorry, Josie.
对不起什么  跟扎拉重新好上吗
For what? Falling back into Zarah?
我之前都死了
I was dead.
但是你没死
Yeah, but you're not dead.
你活生生地在这里
You're right here.
看着我  莱顿
Look at me, Layton.
我不在乎你孩子的母亲是谁
I don't care who the mother of your child is.
你知道是谁对我下的毒手
You know who did this to me.
梅兰妮
Melanie.
我不得不结盟  这是唯一的出路
I had to make the alliance. It was the only way.
为了她的计划  你牺牲了35名车尾人
You sacrificed 35 Tailies to her plan.
我说服他们参加抗争
The people that I convinced to fight.
我想和他们一起死去
I wanted to die with them.
而现在我们完全没有实现对他们的承诺
And now you've given them nothing that we promised.
你的领导能力也有问题
And your leadership is in question.
乔茜  这个任务
Josie, this mission--
是梅兰妮的任务
It's Melanie's mission.
没错  我相信工程师
Yes, I believe the Engineers.
我相信这是我们最好的机会
I believe that this is our best chance,
而我有义务保护它不受到威尔福德先生的破坏
and now it is my job to defend it from Mr. Wilford.
革命分子无法成为优秀的政治家
Revolutionaries make terrible politicians.
他们现在就是这么看你的
That's how they see you now.
我还是车尾人  乔茜
I am still a Tailie, Josie.
你需要我的支持  不然你就会失去人心
And you need my support, or you'll lose them.
还是没有大麻吗
Still no marijuana?
你出卖了自己是走私犯的身份
You sold yourself as a smuggler.
我走私我自豪  朋友
Well, I smuggle smugly, my friend.
我刚刚从边境来
I just came from the border,
我有机会参与一些高层贸易谈判的会议
where I was privy to some high-level trade talks.
这次我的建议是收下橄榄
My advice at this time would be have another olive,
耐心等待
be patient.
我不擅长耐心等待
Not my strong suit.
那如果你没有大麻
So if you got no weed...
怎么
Yes?
我真不想你坐在这里
I really don't want you sitting up here.
别见怪
No offense.
只是这样看起来不好
It just looks bad,
跟车尾人做生意
you know, dealing with the Tail?
抱歉  莱茨  你得给我看
I'm sorry, Lights. You gotta show me.
看到没  你觉得这看起来像什么
See? What's that look like to you?
你肯定有看到什么
You must've seen something.
他们用头套罩住了我  就在几秒钟之内
They blackbagged me. It happened in seconds.
我看到他们跑掉了  他们戴着面具
I saw them run away. They had masks.
把手指一起带走了
Yeah, took the fingers with them.
传闻说是维修队的人
Track talk says it was the Breachmen.
我什么也不会说
I'm not saying nothing.
他们只会更暴力地对待我
They'll just come gunning for me harder.
她想要在集市里开一个维修铺
She was trying to open a repair stall in the market.
如果大家对我们仍有偏见
How free's a Tail
车尾人怎么算是自由
if everyone's still prejudiced against us?
车尾一心  我们会保护自己的
Hey, one Tail, all right? We'll protect ourselves.
大家都知道如何相互保护  防守阵线
You all know how to protect each other and hold the line.
不要越界  交给我们就好了
Just don't cross it. We got this.
有我支持你
Yeah, and I got you.
我会查清楚是谁干的
I'm gonna find out who did this,
他们不会再来了
and they're not coming back, okay?
我之前说过了  威尔福德的人已经到这边了
I said it before-- Wilford's already got people here.
维修队的人很喜欢威尔福德  讨厌车尾人
Yeah, the Breachmen love Wilford and hate Tailies.
但是那证明不了什么
But that's not proof of anything.
有人想把上帝的恐惧灌输给我们
Someone's trying to throw the fear of God into us,
他们就在名单的首位
and they're top of the list.
罗切  你要不要和她一起去找维修队的人
Roche, you wanna go with her to visit the Breachmen?
-不太想  -谢谢
- Not really, no. - Thank you.
我讨厌维修队的人
Breachmen. I hate these guys.
我以前是警察  所以像我那样做就好了
Well, I used to be police, so just do what I do.
怎么做  把他们当成消防员来对待
What's that? Think of them as firemen.
你不能就这样闯进来
You can't just chip in here.
我也很高兴见到你  波吉
Nice to see you, too, Boki.
不至于不至于
Well, I wouldn't go that far.
是的  但我们这次是来登门拜访他
No, but we're paying him the courtesy of a house call.
最近谁有戴面具
So who's been wearing masks lately?
去茶室袭击车尾人
Attacking Tailies up by the Tea Room?
有人吗
Anyone?
放下砝码
Weights down.
维修队太过听从威尔福德的话了
This Guild drinks an awful lot of Wilford Kool-Aid,
对吗
don't you?
我们很多人都很高兴他回来了
A lot of us are glad that he's back.
对于砍人手指的事你们有什么要说的吗
Well, what do you gotta say about cutting off people's fingers?
你们可以边上油边说话  对吧
Hey, you boys can oil up and talk at the same time, right?
干嘛那么紧张  提尔警探
Why so tense, Detective Till?
我说不好
I don't know.
你们的人看上去比我壮得多
You guys seem a lot more jacked than me.
嗯  我们在这榨取世界上最后的类固醇
Yeah, we're juicing the world's last steroids up in here.
你也算是半个名人了
You are half-ass famous.
那个引领了革命的司闸员
The Brakemen helped lead the revolution.
正是我  你的人那个时候在哪呢
That's me. Where was your Guild?
就在这  我们当时在哀悼
Right here. We were in mourning.
是的  当时我们发现威尔福德甚至不在火车头
Yeah, when we found out Wilford wasn't even in the Engine,
这对我们是极大的创伤
it was...very traumatic.
所以  我们对革命置身事外
And so we sat it out,
就像我们也不会参与你们的民主实验一样
just like we'll be sitting out your democratic experiment.
我们不需要攻击任何人
We don't need to attack nobody.
我们就在这等待着
We'll be right here waiting...
他的到来
for him.
职责  荣耀  秩序
我的天呐
Holy shit.
-当着我的面  -你告诉他试试
- On my watch? - Don't you dare tell him.
嗨  我  我是艾莉克斯的妈妈
Hi. I'm, um, Alex's mom.
-梅兰妮  -上帝啊
- Melanie. - Oh, my God.
你自己看着办吧  艾莉克斯
You're on your own, Alex.
这你不用担心
Don't worry about that.
快点
Hurry up.
这床不错
It's a nice bunk.
我们可以装饰它们  但是这些床都差不多
We get to decorate them, but they're all the same.
除了威尔福德的床
Except for Wilford's.
你把这装饰的很棒
Well, you made it nice.
我用这个来形象化我们的路线
I use this to visualize our route.
我也是  同样的技巧
I, um--me too. Same trick.
毕竟  我们师出同门
Well, we did have the same teacher.
我以前常常画你
I used to draw you
想象着你的样子
to picture what you looked like.
我也一直在描绘你的脸
I pictured your face, too, all the time.
你太有天赋了
You're so talented.
威尔福德说你是他见过的最厉害的司机
Wilford says you're the best driver he's ever seen.
落基山脉测试轨道
Rocky Mountain Test Track.
碎颈轨道
Neckbreaker.
这次不会
Not this time, though.
当雪国列车达到伯绍德曲线的时候
When Snowpiercer gets to the Berthoud Curve,
大爱丽丝会在后面这个位置
Big Alice will be all the way back here.
她的所有能量
All her power and strength
会让雪国列车通过这条疯狂的垂直线
will get Snowpiercer though this crazy vertical.
布雷斯劳尔气象站
然后  到达这个最高点时  你必须出去
Then, at the highest peak, you have to get out
乘坐雪橇一路回到研究站
and take the sled all the way back to the station.
是的  然后你们去做最重要的部分
Yup, and then you guys do the most important part:
放出一串气象气球
lay a string of weather balloons
横穿白令海大桥
across the Bering Sea Bridge,
低入西伯利亚  中国
down into Siberia, China,
高至喜马拉雅山
up into the Himalaya.
之后我们还要在一个月内
Then we have to circle back to the station
重回站点接你
and pick you up in a month.
是的
Yeah.
这可真疯狂啊  妈妈
That is some crazy shit, Mom.
-你在做什么  -感受列车
- What are you doing? - Feeling the train.
她会告诉你她的情况
She lets you know how she's doing.
雪国列车已经进入了前方的山脉
Snowpiercer's already in the mountains up ahead.
你能感觉得到
You can feel that?
我想你可能也有一个车轮错位了
I think you might have a wheel out of alignment too.
最好去检查下
Better check.
我们得走了
We need to go.
零件换食物
Parts for food.
你和威尔福德面对面达成协定了吗
You cut that deal face-to-face with Wilford?
建立交易
Established trade.
还没有  不过他会同意的
It's not done yet, but he'll go for it.
这正是我担心的事
That must be what worries me.
他是一个爱嫉妒的人
He's a jealous man.
当他选择你的时候
You know, when he chooses you,
你就进入了他的场地
you enter his court.
一开始很棒  他是个很棒的人
It's amazing at first. He's amazing.
然后刀锋就暴露出来
And then the knives come out.
他以分裂人们为乐
He divides people for sport.
梅兰妮和我不允许他这么做
Melanie and I refused to let him.
这就是为什么大爱丽丝是一个"禁本区"吗
Is that why Big Alice is a Ben-Free Zone?
可能吧
Probably.
他嫉妒的不是普通的
His brand of jealousy isn't about anything normal
像爱  背叛或是性爱的事
like love or betrayal or sex.
是关于控制
It's just about control.
我们或许要找个方法利用这点
We might have to find a way to use that.
是啊
Yeah, we might,
但是我们还得和他一起穿过大半个世界
but we still have to go halfway across the world with him,
所以不论你有什么计划
so whatever your plans are...
不保留秘密
No secrets.
我们会一起回到梅兰妮那里
We'll get back to Melanie together.
我哥们怎么样了
How's my boy?
零下71度
96 below.
54分钟  历史最高纪录
54 minutes. Best he's ever done.
他还需要再降温  时间也要更长
He needs to go colder. Longer.
我们还有几个疗法
Well, we have a few more treatments.
-有一整个月时间吗  -一半
- Do we have the full month? - Count on half that.
她还在那么做吗
Is she still doing that?
她说有个车轮错位
She said there's a wheel out of alignment.
然后呢
And?
我问了驾驶的人  她是对的
Well, I asked the Drive Train guys, and she's right.
第9节车厢  前负重轮  左后轮
Car 9, front bogie, left rear.
就在兵舍下  我们都没看到
Right under the barracks, and none of us even saw it.
你没有变得多愁善感吧
You're not going sentimental on me, are you?
没有
No.
我们想要她下车
We want her off this train.
看着我
Look at me.
我要听你说出口
I want to hear you say it.
我们想要她下车
We want her off this train.
爱丽丝  我们在下坡了
Alice, we are on descent.
你好  梅兰妮
Hello, Melanie.
你为你的盛大退场穿上毛线衫了吗
Have you got your woolies on for your grand exit?
还没  但你就快除掉我了  乔瑟夫
No, not yet, but you're nearly rid of me, Joseph.
那么本着这样的合作精神
Oh, well, in that spirit of cooperation,
艾莉克斯将会负责驾驶
Alex will be in the driver's seat.
我觉得
I think it's only fitting
她开车送她妈妈进入来世最合适  你们说呢
she drive her mother into the great beyond, don't the rest of you?
收到
Roger that.
很高兴有你的加入  工程师
Glad to have you, Engineer.
收到  雪国列车
Roger, Snowpiercer.
我们看到你在接近曲线了
We see that you're approaching the curve.
还有不到一分钟
Less than a minute away.
但我们已经遭遇了第一个减速带
But we have hit our first little speed bump.
我猜猜
Oh, let me guess.
雪国列车没有你预期的储量
Snowpiercer doesn't quite have the reserves you anticipated.
我们有一个解决方法
We have a solution.
听好了
All right, listen up.
要想登上山顶  我们需要
To make over the top, we're gonna need
从头等厢和二等厢吸收能量
to pull power from First and Second Class.
唯一的生命支援将在
The only life support will be
诊所车厢和集合点
in the clinic cars and muster stations.
我们将在...后需要额外的汽油
And we're gonna need the extra juice in...
-25分钟  -25分钟
- 25 minutes. - 25 minutes?
-让所有人去集合点  -你能做到  露丝
- To get everyone to muster? - You can do this, Ruth.
我知道你可以
I know you can.
大家坐稳了  会有剧烈晃动
Everyone, hold on. We're coming in hot.
大家还好吗
Everyone okay?
好的  莱顿先生  你跟我来
All right, then, Mr. Layton. You're with me.
如果梅兰妮没有让我们出轨的话
If Melanie doesn't derail us.
紧急状况  紧急状况
Emergency, emergency.
头等厢和二等厢前往夜车
First and Second Class to the Nightcar.
三等厢去农业区或者食堂
Third to the Ag-Sec or Mess Hall.
紧急状况  集合点
Emergency, muster stations...
-快点  -请
- Keep moving. - Please...
一直走到底
All the way to the end.
安德烈  你去哪
Andre, where are you going?
我们要在夜车集合
We're mustering in the Nightcar.
他们不会转移诊所里的病人
Yeah, they're not moving the patients from the clinic.
-你要去见乔茜  -她一个人
- You're gonna see Josie? - She's there all alone.
嗯  去找她吧  这边走  快
Yeah, go be with her. Right this way, guys. Come on.
一直走到底
All the way to the end.
二等厢进入曲线
The Second Class is entering the curve.
也就是说  扶稳了
That is to say, prepare to brace.
谢谢
Thank you.
天啊  见鬼  特里斯坦
Oh, God. For pity's sake, Tristan.
好了  大家冷静
All right, all right, nice and calm now, everyone.
请去集合点
Muster stations, please.
我要看看
I need to see.
冷静  过去
Nice and calm. Move.
这边
This way.
好了  人走完了  关门
All right, car clear. Sealing up.
爱丽丝  我们在爬坡了
Alice, we're on ascent.
-山顶天气更好吗  哈维  -恐怕没有
- Is the weather any better up top, Javi? - I'm afraid not.
我们得先上去
We gotta get up there first.
我们的速度降得太快
Our speed is dropping too fast.
还要多久才能抽取额外的能量
How much longer until we can draw that extra power?
还要几分钟
A few more minutes.
我们还在让大家前往集合点
We're still getting everyone to muster stations.
可能会晚几分钟
Could be a few minutes too late.
我觉得我们做不到  梅兰妮
I just don't see how we're gonna make it, Melanie.
解决办法很简单  我们必须
The solution is simple: the very moment we hit
提前激活助推器  丢吗
the booster will have to be much earlier, won't it?
在曲线前就激活
Hit the boosters before the curve?
那样速度会太快  我们会出轨
That's too much speed. We'll derail.
我想这是教艾莉克斯的时刻
I believe we've found a teaching moment for Alex.
她得保持速度  但不能太快  让我们出轨
She'll have to keep up speed, but not so fast that she derails us
那样我们都会死
and we all die.
她能做到  她能应付
She can do it. She can handle it.
雪国列车
Snowpiercer?
回话  雪国列车
Come in, Snowpiercer.
收到  大爱丽丝
Copy, Big Alice.
你可以的  艾莉
You got this, Allie.
松开刹车  保持镇静
Just lay off your brakes and keep your nerve.
再次合作是不是很棒  梅兰妮
Isn't it nice to work as a team again, Melanie?
集合点  快进来
Muster stations. Come in, come in.
一个崭新的节目即将开始
A brand new show is about to begin.
梅兰妮在做任务  而威尔福德先生
Melanie is on a mission, and Mr. Wilford is...
她是怎么了
The hell is going on with her?
她快崩溃了  罗切
She's cracking, Roche.
我们都一样  如果你还没注意到的话
We all are, if you haven't noticed.
- 安全  已经关门做好准备  - 露丝
- All clear. Sealed and ready. - Ruth.
火车头  现在什么情况
Engine, how are we doing?
所有乘客都到了集合点
All passengers are at muster.
准备关闭  万福玛利亚
Ready for shutdown. And hail bloody Mary.
交给我们  露丝  阿门
We'll take it, Ruth. Amen.
-立刻关掉车厢电源  -收到
- Power down the cars now! - Copy!
已关掉
Powered down.
速度还在西江
Speed's still falling.
还要速度  从储藏间抽取
More speed. Take it from storage.
我已经抽了  我们必须激活助推器
I already have. We have to hit the booster.
我们就要到曲线了
We're almost to the curve.
我们已打开保险
We're armed!
我为你感到骄傲  艾利克斯
I'm proud you're here, Alex.
收到
Copy.
她收到了  如果你没听到的话
She copies, if you didn't hear that.
推她下去
Push her over the hill.
她会再次消失
She'll be gone again.
你想要这次攀爬失败
You want this climb to fall short.
如果你想跟妈妈有更多相处时间的话
If you want to spend more time with Mummy,
那就别激活助推器
just don't hit the booster.
-她激活了  -速度在提升  艾莉
- She's got it. - Speed's climbing, Allie.
保持住
Hold onto it!
如果我们再加速  就会坠下河堤
If we accelerate any more, we'll run ourselves right over the bank.
或者踩刹车  一切看你
Or just tap the brakes. It's up to you.
你可以的  艾莉克斯
You got this, Alex.
感受列车
Just feel the train.
我会让你过去的  梅兰妮
I'll get you there, Melanie.
跟妈妈永别
And it's farewell to Mother!
真精彩  棒极了
Such drama! Bravo!
你做到了
You did it.
你做到了  艾莉
You did it, Allie.
冷锁处见
I'll see you at the cold lock.
该走了  梅兰妮
Time to go, Melanie.
再看着我
Look at me again.
这是我允许你流的最后一滴泪
That's the last tear I'll allow.
以后不会流了
It's the last one you'll get.
拜托  艾莉克斯  独立点
Oh, come on, Alex! Cut the umbilical.
我们刚刚开始一次伟大的冒险
We're at the beginning of a great adventure.
-你去哪  -检查防护服和齿轮保险装置
- Where are you going? - Suit check and gear lock.
得为她下车做好准备
Gotta keep it nice and slow for her drop.
木星
Jupiter.
趴下  木星
Down, Jupiter!
我让你宠她
I let you spoil her.
狗也是
The dog too.
去吧  跟她最后道别
Go on, then. Say your last goodbyes.
你怎么样
How are you doing, huh?
大家喝起来
Everybody, drink.
给我
Here, I'll take that.
我知道威尔福德回来了  但你得振作起来
I know Wilford's back, but you need to get it together.
我们没有准备好迎接这一切
We're not ready for any of this.
-嗯  -又见面了  提尔警探
- Yeah. - Hello again, Detective Till.
罗根牧师  你们认识吗
Pastor Logan. You know each other?
首席司闸员罗切  我当然认识
Lead Brakeman Roche. Of course I do.
你担心我们没准备好什么
And what is it you're worried we're not ready for?
我们没有站稳脚跟
We just never got our feet set.
从没向这些人展示他们可以信任一个新系统
Never showed these people they could trust a new system,
而如今威尔福德又回到了他们脑子里
and now Wilford's back in their heads.
你发现你有什么变化吗
Do you see what's changed in you?
在这混乱之中
Through all this turmoil,
-你担心的却是他们的灵魂  -是啊
- you're concerned about their souls now. - Yeah.
我承认  这个我有很多
And I'll admit, I've got a stash of them.
我不认为圣克里斯托弗会起任何作用
Yeah, I don't think St. Christopher's gonna do it.
这值得再三强调
Well, it bears repeating...
旅程永无止境
The journey never ends.
希望是真的  乔茜
The hope is real, Josie.
梅兰妮要下车去证明
Melanie's getting off the train to prove it.
梅兰妮
Melanie.
我皮肤冻住的时候
While my skin was freezing over,
我蜷缩起来
I curled up
保住这只手
and protected this hand.
因为我只需要一个拳头
'Cause one fist is all I need.
你要当爹了
You're going to be a father.
这是你的孩子
Your child.
那是我们所有人的指明灯
That's a guiding light for all of us.
如果梅兰妮的任务是
And if Melanie's mission is our only hope
我们下车的唯一希望
to ever get off this train,
那我们的人现在就有了一个新的事业
then our people have a new cause now.
露丝
Ruth.
我去准备过境
I'll go and prepare the crossing.
谢谢
Thank you.
听着  我想你知道你的重心是什么
Look, I--I think you know what your priorities are.
你想要我给你说一遍  看看我记住没有吗
Yeah, you want me to run it by you to see if I got it?
-保护科学  -这是最重要的
- Protect the science. - Number one.
要做到这个  我得抵挡住
Yeah, to do that, I'll have to hold off
创造了这个世界的夸大狂
the megalomaniac who created this world
他还想要重新夺回权力
and wants to get power back again.
他已经有了一些支持者
And he's already got some supporters on his side.
不会更多了
Yeah, that's about the size of it.
这让我相信
Which leads me to believe
他或许一开始就不想要
that maybe he didn't want anybody to get off this train
下车  重新移民地球
and recolonize the Earth in the first place.
我跟你说清楚
Just so we're clear,
这次任务成功与否看的是数据
the success of this mission will be measured in data,
而不是我的存活
not my survival.
祝你好运  安德烈
Good luck, Andre.
祝你好运  梅兰妮
Good luck, Melanie.
派克  你可以出来了  我看到你了
Pike, you can come on out. I see you.
被你抓到我大便了  兄弟
Aw, you caught me on the shitter, brother.
听着  我想要你再次
Listen, I want you to link back up
跟另一辆车的人脉联系
with your connect in the other train.
我会给你一条运输路线
I'm giving you a pipeline.
-认真的吗  -但只能运大麻
- You're serious? - But only weed.
而且我指定你能运什么过去
And I get to tell you what goes the other way.
我不会让你失望的
I won't let you down, man.
你可以信任莱顿
You can trust Layton.
他是好人
He's a good man.
他公正
He's just,
跟你一样
and so are you.
好男人和好女人
Well, good men and women
在这里似乎很难保持善良  是吗
don't seem to stay good long doing this, do they?
答应我你会照顾艾莉克斯
Please promise me you'll look after Alex.
我
I just--
我想知道有人
I wanna know someone's...
陪着她
there for her.
如果是你的话  那对我会很重要
It would mean a lot to me if it was you.
我当然会
Of course I will.
我答应你
You have my word.
谢谢
Thank you.
这里是雪国列车
This is Snowpiercer.
我们准备过境
We are ready to cross.
很高兴你能来
I'm glad you could make it.
工程师
Engineer.
我们会在你回来的时候
We'll all be waiting for you right here
在这等你
when you get back.
到达后立刻给防护服充电
So you'll recharge the suit immediately upon arrival.
评估损伤  给庇护所打底漆
Assess the damage. Prime the shelter.
我担心的就是损伤
Well, the damage is what I'm worried about.
我会在那即兴发挥
I'll find things to improvise with there.
别担心
Don't worry.
你知道他故意给你施加压力
You know he put that pressure on you on purpose.
当他让你驾驶列车的时候
When he made you drive the train.
当他命令你和雪国列车断开的时候
And when he ordered you to disconnect Snowpiercer
只因他想要你的良心背负着那些死亡
just 'cause he wanted all that death on your conscience.
我想让你知道
I just want you to know,
那是他的残忍
that's his cruelty.
不是你的
It is not yours.
永远别忘记
Never forget that.
这不是你的错
It's not your fault.
我想要你再多留一会儿
I wanted to keep you here longer.
我很想要踩刹车
I wanted to hit the brakes so bad.
但我们做了我们必须做的事
But we did what we have to do.
我们不是你所想的那样
Hey, we're not who you think over there,
所以如果你有什么需要
so if you ever need anything,
这边有你可以信任的人
there are people you can trust.
谢谢
Thank you.
我爱你  艾莉
I love you, Allie.
一个月后见  妈
I'll see you in a month, Mom.
闪光信号就是下车点
Flare marks the drop point.
好了  准备好
All right, guys. Here we go.
三秒后发射  三  二  一
Fire in three, two, one.